Register of the James Bunyan Papers, 1917-1963
Hoover Institution Archives
James Bunyan Papers,
1917-1963
75064
Bunyan, James, 1898-
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Excerpts from published sources, documents, and notes (primarily in Russian), relating to the Ukrainian government, Russia, Siberia, and the Far Eastern Republic during the Russian Civil War in 1919, used by J. Bunyan as research material for his book, The Bolshevik Revolution, 1917-1918 (1934); drafts, notes, charts, and printed matter (primarily in English), relating to Soviet economic, administrative, agricultural, and industrial organization and planning, 1917-1963, used by J. Bunyan as research material for his book, The Origin of Forced Labor in the Soviet State, 1917-1921 (1967); and drafts of the latter book.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Agriculture--Soviet Union.; Forced labor--Soviet Union.; Dal'nevostochnaia Respublika.; Siberia (Russia)--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--Economic policy.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union--Industries.; Soviet Union--Politics and government.; Ukraine--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Ukraine.
Container List
- SUBJECT FILE, 1919. (Box 1.)
  Excerpts from published sources (typewritten and handwritten), documents, notes, etc., relating to the Ukrainian government, Russia, Siberia, and the Far Eastern Republic during the Russian Civil War in 1919, collected by James Bunyan, author of The Bolshevik Revolution, 1917-1918. Primarily in Russian.
  - Russian Civil war, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Agriculture, labor and economy
    - Baltic provinces
    - CHEKA (Chrezvychainaia Kommissiia po bor'be s kontrrevoliutsiei i sabotazhem)
    - Communist International
    - Deniken, General Anton Ivanovich
    - Don Cossacks
    - Education and culture
    - Food supply
    - Land possession
    - Railroads and transportation
    - Report of Commander, U.S. Naval Forces in Northern Russia, N. A.McCully, June 30, 1919
    - Russian Communist (Bolshevik) Party
    - Russian Social Democrat Workers Party
    - Siberia and the Far Eastern Republic
    - Socialist-Revolutionary Party
    - Miscellaneous
  - Ukrainian Government, 1919
    - Chicherin's radiogram and notes to the Ukrainian Minister of Foreign Affairs, Chekhovskii, January 6, 1919 (in Russian)
    - Commander-in-Chief, Ukrainian Red Army, memo to the Ukrainian Council of Defense, May 8, 1919 (in Russian)
    - Fedenko, Panas (Social-Democrat), on insurrection, 1919 (in Russian)
    - Grigoriev's Proclamation, May 7, 1919 (in Russian)
    - Khar'kov faction of the organizational committee of the Ukrainian Independent Social-Democratic Workers Party, resolution on the relationship to the Ukrainian Communist Party, December 1918 (in Russian)
    - Mazurenko, Iurii
    - Provisional Worker-Peasant Government of the Ukraine, declaration, January 26, 1919
    - Third All-Ukrainian Congress of Soviets, February 1919
    - Ukrainian Council of the Worker-Peasant Defense, appeal, May 10, 1919 (in Russian)
    - Ukrainian Diplomatic Mission, address to Poland, December 12, 1919 (in Russian)
    - Ukrainian Independent Social-Democratic Party
    - Ukrainian Party of Socialist-Revolutionaries, declaration, February 28, 1919 (in Russian)
    - Ukrainian Peoples Republic, proclamation to the people, December 2, 1919 (in Russian)
    - Ukrainian-Polish Diplomatic Conference in Warsaw, August 1919
    - Ukrainian Soviet Government, note to French Minister of Foreign Affiars on evacuation of troops, undated (in Russian)
    - Miscellaneous
- INCREMENT, May 1977. (Box 2.)
  Manuscripts, drafts, notes, printed matter, charts, etc., relating to Soviet economic-administrative, agricultural, and industrial organization and planning, 1917-1963, authored and collected by James Bunyan.
  - Average Annual Wage in Industry, Trade, and Construction in the U.S.S.R., undated (Box 2)
  - Economic Planning in the U.S.S.R., undated
  - Evolution of the Administrative Structure of Soviet Industry, 1917-1957, undated
  - Industrial Organization and Planning in the U.S.S.R., 1917-1963, undated
  - The 1963 Model of Soviet Industrial Organization and Planning, undated
  - Present Day Management of Soviet Agriculture, undated
  - Present Day Procedures in Soviet Industrial Organization and Management, undated
  - Recent Trends in Soviet Industrial Planning, undated
  - Soviet industrial organization and management
  - Soviet Inter-Industry Tables, undated
  - The Structure of Soviet Industry in 1950-55 and in 1960, undated
  - Turnover Taxes on Consumers' Goods in the U.S.S.R., October 26, 1961
  - Miscellaneous materials on Soviet economy, industry, management, agriculture, etc.
  - 2 economic-administrative maps (Oversize-package Oversize package)
  - 2 structure of Soviet industrial management charts
- INCREMENT, April 1978. (Box 2-3)
  Preliminary drafts (typewritten carbon copies), with corrections and annotations, of the book The Origin of Forced Labor in the Soviet State, 1917-1921 by James Bunyan.
  - The Origin of Forced Labor in the Soviet State, 1917-1921 (John Hopkins Press, 1967). Preliminary drafts (typewritten carbon copies), with corrections an annotations. (Box 2-3)